TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
yume ni yobare te… nami ni makare te…
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
fukai KAOSU no mori wo nuketara
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
kimi no kokoro de nanika ga kawaru
gin'iro no yoake ga ima
nagai nemuri wo uchikudaku you ni
Concept Design
3D Collaboration
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Digital Zero
Kawami Takuya
kimi no inochi ni PARUSU wo okuru
hitasura ni ikiru tame ni
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
kimi no hitomi no naka umareta bakarino
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
yume no kakera wo tsuyosa ni kaete yuke
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
jidai ni tobikomu yuuki no DIVER
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Sawa Reiko
Nomura Hiroshi
ima no kurushimi ya namida wo
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
afureru chikara douka shinjite
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
kagayaku tame ni tabitate SOLDIER
Production
설마...
No way...
Apa benar...
카이토... 돌아온 거야?!
Kaito... Did you just came back?!
Kaito... Kau sudah kembali, ya?!
어, 어떻게 내가 저기에...
W-Why am I there...
Ke-kenapa aku ada di situ...
혀
A
K
현
All
Ka
현호
Allu
Kab
현혹
Alluri
Kabu
현혹으
Allurin
Kabut
현혹의
Alluring
Kabut Il
현혹의 아
Alluring M
Kabut Ilu
현혹의 안
Alluring Mi
Kabut Ilus
현혹의 안개
Alluring Mis
Kabut Ilusi
현혹의 안개!
Alluring Mist!
Kabut Ilusi!
현혹의 안개! 고
Alluring Mist! G
Kabut Ilusi! G
현혹의 안개! 골
Alluring Mist! Go
Kabut Ilusi! Go
현혹의 안개! 골레
Alluring Mist! Gole
Kabut Ilusi! Gole
현혹의 안개! 골렘
Alluring Mist! Golem
Kabut Ilusi! Golem
현혹의 안개! 골렘오
Alluring Mist! Golemo
Kabut Ilusi! Golemo
현혹의 안개! 골렘온
Alluring Mist! Golemon
Kabut Ilusi! Golemon
서기 2100년.
A. D. 2100.
Tahun 2100 Masehi.
돌연 나타난 악의 프로그램 데리트로스에 의해 전 세계의 아이들이 매지컬 게이트에 갇혀 버렸다.
Due to a sudden appearance by an evil program called Deletloss,
Karena ulah jahat program Deletloss yang muncul secara tiba-tiba,
children all over the world are trapped inside Magical Gate.
anak-anak dari seluruh dunia terperangkap di dalam Magical Gate.
매지컬 게이트를 되찾아 갇힌 친구들을 구해내기 위해, 유우키 켄토는 글라디온과 함께 일어선다.
In order to take Magical Gate back and rescue his friends who are trapped inside,
Untuk merebut kembali Magical Gate dan menyelamatkan teman-teman yang terperangkap,
Yuuki Kento stands up with Gladion.
Yuuki Kento berjuang bersama dengan Gladion.
그런 그들의 앞에 나타난 새로운 적, 쌍둥이 웹나이트, 케르베리온과 오르토리온.
There were new enemies waiting for them: a twin Webknights named Kerberion and Orthorion.
Lalu, di hadapan mereka, muncullah musuh baru; Webknight kembar Kerberion dan Orthorion.
격투 끝에, 켄토와 글라디온은 동물을 조종하는 오르토리온을 쓰러뜨리고,
After the confrontation, Kento and Gladion took down Orthorion who controlled animals,
Setelah pertarungan yang sengit, Kento dan Gladion berhasil mengalahkan Orthorion yang bisa mengendalikan binatang.
아이들과 협력한 끝에 케르베리온의 덫마저 쳐부순다.
and broke through Kerberion's trap by working with Aoi and the others.
Dan berkat bantuan Aoi dan yang lainnya, merekapun berhasil meloloskan diri dari perangkap Kerberion.
다만, 케르베리온과 오르토리온은 최후의 카드가 남아 있었다.
But, Kerberion and Orthorion still had their final trump card.
Tapi, Kerberion dan Orthorion masih punya senjata pamungkas mereka.
굉장한 안개야, 할아버지.
What a terrible fog, isn't it, Grandpa?
Kabutnya tebal sekali ya, Kek?
으음, 이렇게 심한 안개는 처음이야. 1미터 앞도 보이지 않는구나.
Yeah, I've never seen it this thick before. I can't even see through a meter.
Hm, baru pertama kali aku melihat yang separah ini. Bahkan jarak 1 meter sudah tidak terlihat.
왜 그래?
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
다리가?
The bridge...
Jembatannya...
다리가 두 개? 어떻게 된 거야?
Two bridges? What's going on?
Jembatannya ada dua? Bagaimana bisa?
모르겠다. 어제까진 분명히 하나였었는데.
I don't know. There was only one yesterday.
Entahlah. Hingga kemarin, jembatannya hanya ada satu.
어? 봐봐! 켄토야!
Huh? Look! It's Kento!
Wah, lihat, ada Kento di situ!
여기로 오라고 손을 흔들고 있어!
He's waving to tell us to go there!
Dia melambaikan tangan menyuruh kita ke sana!
저 다리야, 할아버지!
That's the right bridge, Grandpa!
Lewat jembatan yang itu saja, Kek!
켄토!
Kento!
뭔 짓이니, 아오이!
What are you doing, Aoi?!
Apa yang kau lakukan, Aoi?!
봐봐, 할아버지!
Look at that, grandpa!
Kakek, lihat itu!
방금은 켄토가 아니었나봐...
That wasn't Kento after all...
Yang tadi itu, bukan Kento, kan...
다녀오겠습니다!
See you later!
Aku pergi ya!
안녕, 미나모.
Good morning, Minamo!
Pagi, Minamo!
안녕. 아침인데 저녁 같네.
Morning! It's still early but it feels like evening, eh?
Pagi! Suasananya seperti sore, ya?
그러게.
Yeah.
Iya, ya.
켄토!
Kento!
-어?
-Huh?
-Hah?
안개가 너무 심해!
What a terrible fog!
Kabutnya benar-benar tebal ya!
정말. 왠지 입고 있는 옷까지 하얗게 되어버릴 것 같아.
Really. It's like the clothes I'm wearing is turning white too.
Iya. Sampai-sampai baju yang dipakai rasanya jadi ikut putih.
에이, 농담하고는 한번!
Man, that's just plain dumb!
Kau ini ada-ada saja!
으아, 엄청 놀랐다... 그래도 여기까지 왔으니 괜찮겠지.
That was close! We should be fine here, I think.
Aku sampai kaget! Tapi di sini pasti sudah aman, ya.
어, 쿄우이치? 어디야? 어디 갔어?
Huh, Kyouichi? Where are you? Where did you go?
Ah, Kyouichi? Kau dimana? Kau kemana?
저건...
That's...
Itu kan...
헬프 미!
Help me!
켄토! 살려줘!
Kento! Save me!
Kento! Tolong aku!
켄토!
Kento!
아야... 켄토!
Ouch... Kento!
A-A-Aduh... Kento!
뭔 짓이야!
What was that for?!
Apa yang kau lakukan?!
사, 사라졌어...?
H-He disappeared...
D-Dia menghilang...
정말이야! 켄토 때문에 나 오토바이에 부딪힐 뻔했다고!
I'm not joking! I almost got hit by a motorcycle because of Kento!
Aku tidak bohong! Gara-gara Kento, hampir saja aku tertabrak motor!
나도 무시당했어. 분명히 켄토였어.
In my case, he ignored me and just left. That was Kento for sure.
Saat aku dikejar anjing, dia juga diam saja dan pergi. Aku yakin itu Kento.
응, 틀림없어!
Yeah, that's right.
Iya, tidak salah lagi.
맞아, 맞아!
True, true!
Benar, benar!
아오이는?
What do you think, Aoi?
Aoi, bagaimana menurutmu?
그 가짜 다리로 가라고 한 거 켄토였지?
You said that Kento led you to a fake bridge, right?
Yang menyuruh kalian melewati jembatan palsu itu Kento, kan?
확실히 내 눈에 보인 건 켄토였지만...
I did saw Kento with my eyes, but..
Memang kelihatannya sih seperti Kento, tapi...
안녕!
Good morning!
Haaai, pagi!
늦잠 잤어! 위험했지만 겨우 세이프!
I overslept! I was almost late but thank goodness I'm not!
Aku ketiduran! Hampir saja aku telat sampai sekolah!
새벽에 이상한 꿈 꿔서. 그리고 또 자 버렸어.
I dreamed of something weird in dawn, and then I slept again.
Pas subuh tadi, aku bermimpi aneh, dan setelah itu aku jadinya tidur lagi, deh.
-켄토!
-어?
-Kento!
-Uh?
-Eh?
-웃을 일이 아니잖아!
-우리에게 사과할 거 있지 않니?
-Don't play dumb!
-You have something to tell to us, don't you?
-Apanya yang 'eh'?!
-Ada hal yang harus kau katakan kepada kami semua.
미안! 내가 잘못했어! 푠타네 토끼집 청소 안 한 거 말이지?
Sorry! My bad! It's about me skipping out from cleaning Pyonta's cage, right?
Maaf! Aku yang salah! Kalian kesal karena aku bolos membersihkan kandang kelinci Pyonta, kan?
그 때 보고 싶은 TV 프로그램이 있었어!
I had a TV program I wanted to watch that time!
Kebetulan saat itu ada acara TV yang ingin kutonton!
어, 그거 아니야?
Huh, wasn't that it?
Eh, bukan masalah itu ya?
아, 그럼, 몰래 아오이 도시락에 소시지 하나 먹긴 했는데-
Ah, then, maybe it's about eating a sausage from Aoi's lunch box..
Oh, iya, mungkin gara-gara aku makan sosisnya Aoi secara diam-diam...
-그 이야기 아니야.
-켄토 그런 녀석이었군!
-We weren't talking about that.
-I didn't thought you were that kind of person!
-Bukan tentang itu.
-Kento ternyata seperti itu, ya.
실망이야!
How deceiving!
Mengecewakan!
-뭔 이야기야.
-시치미 떼지 마!
-What are you talking about anyway?
-Are you trying to fool us?
-Apa yang kalian bicarakan sebenarnya?
-Kamu masih berlagak tidak tahu?
뭔 일인지 알아야 말이지!
But I really don't know what's going on!
Tapi aku benar-benar tidak tahu apa maksud kalian!
알겠다! 친구에게 그런 짓을 해 놓고 사과도 안 하는 놈이랑은 같이 있기 싫어! 가자.
So I see! I don't want to befriend someone who did such thing and doesn't even apologize. Let's just go!
Sudahlah! Aku tidak ingin berteman dengan anak yang tega berbuat seperti itu, tapi minta maaf saja tidak mau. Ayo pergi!
잠깐! 야! 코우지! 쿄우이치! 마모루!
Wait a moment! Hey! Kouji! Kyouichi! Mamoru!
Oi, tunggu! Kouji! Kyouichi! Mamoru!
아오이, 뭔 일이야! 대체 다들 내가 뭘했길래 그래.
Come on, Aoi, tell me, what exactly did I do?
Aoi, tolong beritahu aku, memangnya aku salah apa dengan mereka?
그런 이야기였어.
That's what we were talking about.
Begitulah ceritanya.
설마! 난 모르는 일이야! 뭔가 오해라고!
No way! I don't know about that! There must have been some misunderstanding!
Apa?! Aku tidak tahu apa-apa akan hal itu! Pasti ada kesalahan!
믿어줘! 아, 그거, 내가 본 녀석이랑 같은 놈이겠다. 응, 아오이?
Trust me! Ah, that guy - it must be the same guy who I saw, right, Aoi?
Percayalah padaku! Aah, pasti dia orang yang sama dengan yang kulihat dalam mimpi. Ya kan, Aoi?
알았어! 아니, 알고 있었어. 그건 진짜 켄토가 아니라는 걸.
I knew it! No, I had known it. That was not the real Kento.
Aku tahu! Iya, dari tadi aku sudah tahu kalau itu pasti bukan Kento yang sesungguhnya.
그래서 나는 급히 브레이크 버튼을 눌렀어.
That's why I pushed the brake button in haste.
Karena itulah aku langsung menekan rem.
아오이.
Aoi.
누가 뭐라고 해도, 나는 켄토를 믿어! 반드시, 뭔가 비밀이 있어.
No matter what they say, I trust you, Kento! There must be a secret behind this case.
Biar apapun yang dikatakan orang, aku tetap percaya padamu! Pasti ada suatu rahasia di balik ini.
응. 분명히 이 안개 때문일 거야.
Yeah. It must be because of this fog.
Ya. Pasti ini gara-gara kabut itu.
도플갱어 현상?
Doppelganger phenomenon?
Fenomena doppelganger?
그래. 존재할 리 없는 또 하나의 자신을 보게 되는 걸 뜻하지.
Yes. It's a phenomenon of seeing your other self that shouldn't have existed.
Iya. Itu adalah sebutan kalau kita melihat seorang diri kita yang lain yang seharusnya tidak ada.
괴테라는 먼 옛날의 유명한 작가도 자신을 만났었다는 기록을 남기고 있어.
A famous writer from long ago named Goethe also wrote that he met his other self.
Seorang pengarang terkenal dari jaman dulu yang bernama Goethe juga menuliskan bahwa ia pernah bertemu dengan bayangannya.
그런 일이 정말 가능해?
Is that really possible?
Apa itu mungkin?
모르겠다. 복잡한 뇌의 메커니즘을 통해 일어나는 현상일 거라 생각되는구나.
I don't know. It was thought to be a phenomenon caused by the complex mechanism of brain.
Entahlah. Itu adalah suatu fenomena yang ditimbulkan oleh mekanisme otak yang sangat rumit.
그렇지만, 어째서 그 켄토의 분신은 아이들에게 못된 짓을 한 걸까요?
But, why did Kento's other self cause problems to everyone else?
Tapi, kenapa Kento yang satunya lagi selalu mengganggu teman-temannya yang lain?
마치 켄토가 쌍둥이여서 한쪽은 지금 여기 있는 켄토와 정반대의 켄토를 보는 것 같았어.
It's like, Kento has a twin, but his twin is the complete opposite from the Kento who's in here right now.
Dia seperti kembaran Kento, tapi tingkah laku Kento yang itu sangat bertolak belakang dengan Kento yang sedang di sini.
쌍둥이?
Twin?
Kembar?
안개 자체의 성분에 특이한 점은 없습니다. 그런데, 안개는 아주 조금씩이긴 하지만, 회전하고 있습니다.
I don't see anything wrong in the foggy area, except that the fog is revolving slowly.
Selain kabut yang tebal ini, tidak terlihat keanehan yang lain, hanya saja, kabut ini terus berputar dengan sangat pelan.
-회전하고 있다고?
-예.
-Revolving?
-Yes.
-Berputar?
-Benar.
그러니까 바람이 불어도 다이버랜드 주변을 빙글빙글 돌 뿐, 사라지지 않고 있는 겁니다.
Even if the wind's blowing, it will keep revolving and won't leave from Diverland and its surrounding.
Biar ditiup angin sekalipun, kabutnya hanya bergerak memutar dan tidak mau beranjak dari sekitar Diverland.
마치 의지를 가지고 있는 듯 한 안개로군...
It's like the fog is acting on its own...
Seakan-akan kabut ini memiliki pikiran...
글라디온으로부터의 출격지령이야. 역시 이 안개는...
It's an order to sort out from Gladion. So this fog is as well...
Ini adalah panggilan dari Gladion untuk bergerak. Jadi kabut ini...
잠깐, 나 화장실 좀!
Uh, I need to go to toilet!
Maaf ya, aku mau ke toilet dulu!
좋아! 매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
Alright! Plug it to Magical Gate!
Nah! Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
프로그램 복구, 75 퍼센트.
Program recovery, 75 percent.
Pemulihan program, 75 persen.
글라디온, 무슨 일이 일어난 거야?
Gladion, what the heck is going on?
Gladion, apa yang sedang terjadi?
또 새로운 웹나이트가 한 짓이야?
Is it a new Webknight's work again?
Apa ini ulah Webknight yang baru?
그게, 나도 이런 이상한 힘을 갖는 자가 있으리라고는 생각도 못 했어.
Truth is, I also didn't know there's someone who wields such strange power like this before.
Aku juga tidak tahu kalau ada Webknight yang memiliki kemampuan aneh seperti ini.
글라디온도 몰랐어?
Even Gladion didn't know?
Kaupun tidak tahu?
정말 새로운 의문점이야뾰꼬.
Truly a new mystery-pyoko.
Ini benar-benar misteri-pyoko.
그렇다. 지금까지 느낀 적 없는, 묘한 사악함이 느껴진다. 그것도 둘씩이나.
Yes. I feel a strange Evil Aura that I've never felt before. Moreover, there's two of them.
Iya. Aku merasakan hawa jahat aneh yang belum kurasakan sebelumnya. Bahkan ada dua.
사악한 기운이 둘...
Two Evil Auras...
Dua hawa jahat...
그래. 상대의 정체를 모른 채 전장으로 가는 건 위험한 일이다.
That's right. It's dangerous to go to the battlefield while you still don't know about your enemy.
Hm. Resikonya besar sekali untuk maju ke medan perang tanpa mengetahui identitas lawan.
그래도 갈까, 켄토?
Knowing so, do you still want to go, Kento?
Apa kau tetap mau bertarung, Kento?
당연하지! 친구한테 이런 이상한 오해를 받고 가만히 있을 순 없잖아?
That's obvious! I can't stay still when I got such weird misunderstanding from my friends!
Tentu saja! Mana bisa aku diam saja membiarkan teman-temanku jadi salah paham terhadapku!
그럼! 웹다이브해라! 켄토!
Well then! Webdive, Kento!
Bagus! Kalau begitu, Webdive, Kento!
응!
Alright!
Baik!
yume ni yobare te... nami ni makare te...
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
fukai KAOSU no mori wo nuketara
kimi no kokoro de nanika ga kawaru
gin'iro no yoake ga ima
nagai nemuri wo uchikudaku you ni
kimi no inochi ni PARUSU wo okuru
hitasura ni ikiru tame ni
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot.
kimi no hitomi no naka umareta bakarino
yume no kakera wo tsuyosa ni kaete yuke
jidai ni tobikomu yuuki no DIVER
ima no kurushimi ya namida wo
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
afureru chikara douka shinjite
kagayaku tame ni tabitate SOLDIER
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
kumo no kirema ni hikari ga mieru
subete shizuka ni shinkashiteiru
omoi de wo tokashinagara
kimi wo yusaburu unmei no you na
sekai ga sotto tobira wo akeru
ashita e to mukau tame ni
kanashimi ni tamesare itsudatte hito wa
yami no moufu ni matanige komukeredo
jidai wo dakishime kodoku na DIVER
yuruginai ai ya yasashi sa
sagashiateta toki mirai de kimi ga
ikiteku shouko mo mitsukaru
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
jidai wo dakishime kodoku na DIVER
yuruginai ai ya yasashi sa
atsui omoi wo itsu mo shinjite
kagayaku tame ni tabitate SOLDIER
저건... 글라디온!
That's... Gladion!
Itu, kan... Gladion!
Brought to you by Subdiver
켄토. 현혹되지 마라. 저건 네가 보았던 또 하나의 너와 같은 도플갱어다!
Don't be deceived, Kento. It's the same as the other self you'd seen: a doppelganger!
Kento, jangan ragu. Itu adalah diriku yang lain, seperti yang pernah kau lihat sebelumnya-- doppelganger!
그렇구나. 헤! 그냥 입체영상이잖아!
I see. Heh! Turns out it's just a mere virtual image!
Begitu ya. Hah! Ternyata cuma bayangan tiga dimensi!
원한을 갚을 때가 왔다. 각오하는 게 좋을 게다, 글라디온!
Time to have our revenge. You'd better be prepared, Gladion!
Saatnya pembalasan telah tiba. Bersiaplah, Gladion!
뭐야, 저 녀석...
What the heck is he doing?
Apa yang mereka lakukan?
설, 설마, 케르베리온과 오르토리온인가.
A-are they Kerberion and Orthorion?
A-Apakah mereka Kerberion dan Orthorion?
그게 맞아뾰꼬.
That's right-pyoko.
Itu benar-pyoko.
저 녀석은 케르베리온과 오르토리온이 합체한 웹나이트뾰꼬.
That's a combined Webknight of Kerberion and Orthorion-pyoko.
Itu adalah Webknight gabungan dari Kerberion dan Orthorion-pyoko.
역시 그랬군.
So I see.
Oh, ternyata begitu...
우리 이름은 골렘온. 완벽한 웹나이트다!
Our name is Golemon, the perfect Webknight!
Namaku adalah Golemon, Webknight yang sempurna!
13명의 웹나이트 중 제일의 방어력을 지닌 오르토리온과 뛰어난 공격력을 지닌 케르베리온의 합체.
Orthorion, with the best defense, and Kerberion, with the best attack among the 13 Webknights, combined...
Gabungan antara Orthorion yang memiliki daya pertahanan terbaik dan Kerberion yang memiliki daya serang terbaik diantara 13 Webknights...
네가 말한 최후의 카드가 이 것이냐!
So this is the trump card you mentioned before!
Jadi ini senjata pamungkas yang mereka maksud!
먼저 치는 쪽이 이겨, 글라디온! 저 녀석을 쓰러뜨리고 토모야와 토모유키 둘을 해방시키자!
Whoever attacks first wins, Gladion! If we defeat him, both Tomoya and Tomoyuki will be freed!
Ini justru kebetulan, Gladion! Kalau bisa mengalahkan dia, kita bisa menyelamatkan Tomoya dan Tomoyuki sekaligus!
가자!
Let's go!
Serang!
자이언트 드릴!
Giant Drill!
어떠냐, 글라디온!
What's wrong, Gladion?
Kenapa, Gladion?
스파이럴 커터!
Spiral Cutter!
그란블레이드가!
The Granblade!
Granblade-nya!
골렘온은 방어할 때 오르토리온이 주체가 되고 공격할 때는 케르베리온이 주체가 된다.
Orthorion takes over Golemon when it's defending, and Kerberion does when it's attacking.
Saat Golemon sedang bertahan, yang mengendalikan adalah Orthorion, dan saat menyerang, Kerberionlah yang memegang kendali.
역시 쌍둥이구나.
Truly something only twins could do.
Kerja sama mereka sungguh hebat.
동화한 웹나이트도 쌍둥이뾰꼬. 이건 이상적뾰꼬.
Synchronized Webdivers are also twins-pyoko. This is an ideal combination-pyoko.
Webdiver yang ada di dalamnya juga kembar-pyoko. Benar-benar kombinasi ideal-pyoko.
감탄하고만 있을 것 같냐!
This is not the time to get impressed!
Ini bukan saatnya untuk terkesan!
우리 둘을 이길 수 있는 것은 이 세상에 존재하지 않아.
There's nothing in this world that can defeat us.
Di dunia ini, tidak ada yang bisa mengalahkan kami berdua.
어떻게 할 테지, 켄토?
What will you do, Kento?
Bagaimana, Kento?
젠장, 분명히 약점이 있을 텐데!
Damn, there must be a weakness somewhere!
Sial, pasti mereka ada kelemahannya!
-그런 건
-있을 리 없지!
-We do not
-have such thing!
-Kelemahan?
-Tak ada hal seperti itu!
그 이전에, 그란블레이드도 없이 어떻게 싸울 생각이지?
Without your precious Granblade, how will you fight?
Lagi pula, tanpa Granblade, bagaimana kau mau bertarung?
우리에겐 여러가지 수가 있거든.
We still have numerous plans for you, though.
Sedangkan kami masih punya banyak senjata.
먹어라!
Eat this!
Terima ini!
그란쉴드를 꺼내! 글라디온!
Take your Granshield out, Gladion!
Keluarkan Granshield, Gladion!
무기 선택: 그란쉴드
Weapon Selection: Granshield
Pilihan Senjata: Granshield
스파이럴 커터!
Spiral Cutter!
언제까지 버틸 것 같냐!
How long will you able to defend like that, huh?
Sampai kapan kau bisa bertahan?!
보이는 둘 중 하나는 도플갱어와 같은 입체영상이야!
One of the two attacks is an image like doppelganger!
Dari dua serangan, salah satunya hanyalah bayangan 3 dimensi seperti doppelganger!
이대로는 안돼뾰꼬!
It'll be dangerous if it stays like this-pyoko!
Kalau begini terus, bisa gawat-pyoko!
하지만, 진짜를 어떻게 찾아내야 하지?
But, how can we find the real one?
Tapi, bagaimana caranya aku bisa tahu yang asli?
글라디온!
Gladion!
글라디온이 적 프로그램과 싸우고 있는 것 같은데...
Gladion seems to be fighting against an enemy program, but...
Kelihatannya Gladion sedang bertarung dengan program musuh, tapi...
아무래도 형세가 불리한 것 같다.
It looks like he's at disadvantage.
Sepertinya ia sedang terdesak.
힘내!
Hang on there!
Berjuanglah!
-힘내, 글라디온!
-Do your best, Gladion!
-You're our only hope,Gladion!
-Ayo berjuang, Gladion!
-Kau pasti bisa, Gladion!
아까는 발끈했지만 다시 잘 생각해 보니 켄토가 그럴 리 없어서 말이야.
We were mad a moment ago, but when we thought about it, Kento wouldn't do such a thing.
Tadi kami memang marah, tapi setelah dipikir baik-baik, Kento memang tidak mungkin melakukan hal seperti itu ya.
맞아.
That's right.
Begitulah.
얘들아...!
Everyone!
Teman-teman!
힘내!
Do the best!
Berjuanglah!
jikuu koete michi e no tobira wo
akete yukeba mirai e no SAIN
aratana kuni hikari ga matataku
bokura ga ima mezashiteru sekai sa
TOGETHER kakemegure
슬슬 끝장을 내 주지!
It's time to finish this!
Saatnya untuk menghabisimu!
motto doko made mo
뭐야?
What the?
Apa itu?
kinou made no kimi to wa chigau sou sa
뭐야, 이건?
What's this?
Apa ini?
새로운 프로그램이 나타났어.
New programs have appeared.
Tiba-tiba muncul program yang baru.
WEBDIVER shinjiyou
프로그램들이 서로 협력하고 있어. 이런 일이...!
The programs are interacting with each other! How can this be...?!
Programnya saling mendukung! Bagaimana mungkin...?
kitto bokura ni wa
hontou no ashita ga matteru
kanarazu dokoka de
쳇, 네이놈...!
Pff, damn you!
Kalian...!
프로그램이 복구되어서 정의의 웹나이트로 부활했어뾰꼬!
The programs have been recovered and revived into the Webknights of justice-pyoko!
Programnya sudah dipulihkan dan dibangkitkan kembali sebagai Webknight pembela kebenaran-pyoko!
좋아, 잘 됐어! 글라디온.
Good, that's great, isn't it, Gladion?
Syukurlah! Syukurlah, Gladion!
네이놈들, 글라디온에게 쓰러졌던 놈들일 테거늘...!
Aren't you guys supposed to be defeated by him?!
Bukankah kalian sudah dikalahkan oleh Gladion?!
어, 어째서...
But how...
Kenapa... kenapa bisa begini...
그, 그란블레이드!
G-Granblade!
자!
Catch!
Tangkap!
좋아!
Alright!
Bagus!
이번에야말로!
Now!
Ayo serang!
자이언트 드릴!
Giant Drill!
지면 안 돼!
We won't lose!
Kami tidak akan kalah!
브레이크 참!
Break Slash!
그란블레이드가 안 먹혀!
Granblade isn't working!
Granblade-nya tidak berhasil!
-말했지?
-우리 둘을 이길 자는 세상에 존재하지 않는다고!
-I told you so.
-There's nothing in this world that can defeat us.
-Sudah kubilang, kan?
-Di dunia ini, tidak ada yang bisa mengalahkan kami!
우리는 완벽하다!
We are a perfect being!
Kami pasangan yang sempurna!
스파이럴 블리자드!
Spiral Blizzard!
켄토!
Kento!
글라디온!
Gladion!
지지 마, 글라디온! 아니, 우리는 질 수 없어!
Don't lose, Gladion! No, we can't afford to lose here!
Jangan kalah, Gladion! Iya, kita tidak boleh sampai kalah!
맞다, 켄토! 골렘온은 몸도 마음도 둘이지만, 우리는 연결된 하나를 가지고 있다!
That's right, Kento! Golemon has two bodies and two minds, but we have the connected one!
Benar, Kento! Biarpun Golemon terdiri dari dua tubuh dan jiwa, tapi jiwa kita terjalin menjadi satu!
알겠다! 두 몸이라면... 둘 다 동시에 공격하자.
I see, two bodies... Let's attack the two bodies at once.
Benar juga! Terdiri dari dua tubuh... kita habisi kedua tubuh itu secara bersamaan.
골렘온은 공격과 방어를 동시에 할 수 없을 터.
Golemon isn't supposed to be able to attack and defend at the same time.
Golemon tidak bisa menyerang dan bertahan sekaligus.
공격 중에는, 저 녀석의 방어는 완벽하지 않아.
While he is attacking, his defense is not perfect.
Waktu sedang menyerang, pertahanannya menjadi tidak sempurna lagi.
무기 선택: 그란매그넘
Weapon Selection: Granmagnum
Pilihan Senjata: Granmagnum
모든 에너지를 그란매그넘에!
Channel all energy to Granmagnum!
Serahkan seluruh energi pada Granmagnum!
뭔 짓이냐!
What are you doing?!
Mau apa kalian?!
그란매그넘! 브레이크 슛!
Granmagnum! Break Shoot!
해냈다! 글라디온!
We did it, Gladion!
Kita berhasil, Gladion!
케르베리온도 오르토리온도 데이터로 전부 회수했어뾰꼬!
I have retrieved all data of both Kerberion and Orthorion-pyoko!
Data Kerberion dan Orthorion sudah dikembalikan-pyoko!
토모야!
Tomoya!
토모유키!
Tomoyuki!
우리 다이버랜드로 돌아왔구나!
We're back at Diverland!
Kita sudah kembali ke Diverland!
어쨌든, 골렘온의 공격은 굉장했어뾰꼬!
Well, Golemon's attack sure was threatening-pyoko!
Serangan Golemon tadi sungguh luar biasa-pyoko!
이젠 더이상 안 되나보다 하고 가슴 졸였어뾰꼬!
For a while, I was afraid about what would happen-pyoko!
Tadi aku sempat khawatir akan bagaimana jadinya-pyoko!
토모야와 토모유키도 해방되었어. 또...
Both Tomoya and Tomoyuki are freed, too. Besides...
Tomoya dan Tomoyuki sudah berhasil diselamatkan. Lagipula...
믿음직한 동료들이 돌아와 주었다.
My comrades whom I can trust on have returned.
Teman-teman yang bisa kuandalkan juga sudah kembali lagi.
알아, 글라디온. 모두 네 소중한 친구들이니까.
I know, Gladion. All of them are your precious friends.
Aku mengerti, Gladion. Mereka adalah teman-temanmu yang sangat berharga.
지금부터는 모두 힘을 합해 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨리자!
From now on, let's take Deletloss down by combining everyone's power!
Mulai sekarang, kita semua akan menyatukan kekuatan untuk mengalahkan Deletloss!
그래!
Right!
Baiklah!
드디어 발견했다.
Found at last.
Akhirnya kutemukan juga.
이 나에게 어울리는 웹다이버를.
A Webdiver who matches just right with me.
Webiver yang pantas untukku.
글라디온, 너를 쓰러뜨릴 자는 바로 나다!
Gladion, I'll be the one who takes you down!
Gladion, yang akan mengalahkanmu adalah aku!
Screenplay
Kishima Nobuaki
Storyboarding
Staging
Kujou Rion
Katou Shigeru
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Karon
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Professor Arisugawa
Tobita Nobuo
Sakuraba Kouji
Maekawa Yuuko
Sanjouji Mamoru
Kurokawa Nami
Ihara Kyouichi
Kakazu Yumi
Shinnou Tomoya
Kawasaki Eriko
Shinnou Tomoyuki
Takagi Reiko
jikuu koete michi e no tobira wo
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Kerberion
Miyashita Michio
Orthorion
Suyama Akio
Garyun
Konishi Katsuyuki
Employee A (Susumu)
Suzumura Ken'ichi
akete yukeba mirai e no SAIN
aratana kuni hikari ga matataku
bokura ga ima mezashiteru sekai sa
TOGETHER kakemegure
motto doko made mo
kinou made no kimi to wa chigau sou sa
WEBDIVER shinjiyou
kitto bokura ni wa
hontou no ashita ga matteru
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
kanarazu dokoka de
Production
Thank you for watching!
Preview for Next Episode
다이버랜드에 우렁차게 울리는 번개. 웹다이버를 데리고
Thunders are roaring in Diverland. With a Webdiver,
Petir-petir bergemuruh di Diverland. Dengan membawa Webdiver,
녀석이 돌아왔어. 글라디온의 라이벌이자 친구, 가륜.
Gladion's rival as well as best friend, Garyun, has finally returned.
Saingan sekaligus sahabat Gladion, Garyun, kembali lagi.
누가 상대이든 나와 글라디온은 질 수 없어!
Whoever the enemy is, Gladion and I can't afford to lose!
Siapapun musuhnya, aku dan Gladion tidak bisa kalah begitu saja!
승부다! 가륜! 이번에야말로 끝을 보자!
We'll have a match, Garyun! We shall settle this once and for all!
Saatnya berduel, Garyun! Mari kita selesaikan kali ini juga!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Stay tuned
for the
next story!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !